The Peninsula Hong Kong is indisputably one
of the most iconic hotels in the entire world.
It has won more awards than I could even mention.
It is a staple of Hong Kong
hospitality, and has been for 97 years.
So of course, I had to do a full review.
I travel around the world and review the very
best hotels out of 50 points in five categories.
The categories, like always, are: The Ambiance,
The Room, The Dining, The Service and The It-
Factor. I'm just a guest staying here for the
very first time, and they did let us know that
the room is officially ready. Let's take a peek
at it before we see the rest of the hotel.
All right, we're going to look at the
room much more in depth a little bit
later in this review. We might even look at
a $30,000 a night suite, but for right now,
let's go take a look around the hotel.
Let's kick off the Ambiance segment with
the Grand Lobby. So as soon as you walk
into the hotel, there is this massive
open space that has not changed for almost
100 years. This lobby is actually split.
Years and years ago, they used to have what's
called a tea party, where on one side of the
room would be the ‘single’ party, and on the other
side of the room were those that were ‘taken’. It
was kind of like the modern day version of a
dating app, where you'd come to these parties
and then meet other singles to potentially
move over to the taken side of the room.
So they kept it the same way after all of
these years. This room really is striking;
it's one of the most beautiful
parts of coming into this hotel,
and it really does start to show you that
history right out of the gate. In fact,
there are over 76 gargoyle faces that are all
in the crown molding and around the different
pillars that are in this room. Now these 76
different faces all have different expressions.
There are many different gods and deities and
different idols that they believe protect the
staff and the guests, which is a theme
in this hotel. So the staff that get
the door for you and greet you here are
called Page boys, and they're called that
because it literally used to be children
that had that job almost 100 years ago.
Now, they kept the same uniform and the same
title all these years, but we'll talk about
the service a little bit later in this review.
Now, continuing with the Ambiance section here,
one of the most interesting and unique
parts of this hotel is The China Clipper.
It is a two helipad rooftop lounge location
where you can literally take helicopter rides
for 1,000 Hong Kong dollars per minute.
The average ride is 18 minutes long.
And once you land from your helicopter, you
can take a ride in one of their signature
Rolls Royces. There are over 20
of these in the Peninsula fleet,
and they're all the same color, Peninsula green.
They set the world record for the most Rolls
ordered in one order in 2006, and they
intend to continue to grow their fleet.
Now up on the eighth floor is the indoor
Roman-inspired heated swimming pool. And in
the summer, they open up the windows here that
look out into Hong Kong and the bay. It is so
serene. It's a Roman bath house, definitely
a standout in the Ambiance of the hotel.
So the spa here has a menu that combines both
Westernized massage techniques and traditional
Chinese medicine. Their signature treatment here
is called the Han treatment, that has pressure
point dry massage mixed with scalp massage, and
it's meant to be a total body reinvigoration.
All right, got my Peninsula spa robe
on, and here in the waiting area,
they have ice that you can put all over your
face or body, a crystal hammam steam room,
dry sauna - so a lot to keep you busy while you're
waiting for your treatment, but I can't wait for
this massage. Let's go in there, see how it is,
and I'll tell you all about it when it's done.
I’ve changed back into my clothes here, I have
one more fun thing to show you in the spa,
which is the couples treatment room. Absolutely
beautiful tub overlooking the harbor here. You've
got real candles behind me. You've got a private
treatment room that you can share. There are 14
treatment rooms here at The Peninsula,
and it's just a really romantic spot.
Now for the gym, and not that you'll be spending
a lot of your time here during your stay,
but it's not that impressive. It's pretty
tightly packed in, the gear is close together,
and there's almost no one here at all
times of the day, and that might be why.
Now the gear itself is pretty modern and
technologically advanced. It does count
your reps, it does count your time, but other
than that, definitely have seen better gyms on
this channel. Let's keep moving.
Let's talk a little bit about themaintenance
and the outdoor areas of the
hotel.
So most of the hotel, of course,
is inside the building, which is segmented
by the old building and the new building.
However, all of the grounds are very
beautiful. One thing that I really love
about the Peninsula is that all of the flowers
that you see throughout the hotel are real,
from the major orchid displays, to
the flowers in the lobby, all real,
all constantly being refreshed
and reset on aregular basis to make sure it looks amazing.
Also, the hotel looks prettyspectacular at night as well.
Connected to the hotel is The Peninsula Arcade,
which is a full shopping mall that's also… kind
of a ghost town. There's international brands,
but also a few that you may know, like Chanel,
for example. But most of this shopping mall
is in the basement of the hotel, and
it's just kind of oddly placed here.
Again, we've seen shopping malls like
at The Shilla, that are done really,
really well. This one is elegant and it definitely
compliments the hotel, but I don't feel like this
is a big selling point for staying here.
There are literally hundreds of high end
items here in the boutique that are all branded
The Peninsula. Probably the largest assortment
of hotel branded items that I've ever seen
at any one of these stays. The Halekulani
came close with their gift shop and how
everything was branded Halekulani in Hawaii,
but I think the Peninsula has them beat - and
the items that they have here are high quality.
They're really well made, and the
Peninsula branding is very subtle,
so, I think they've done it very well.
Plus, this feels like a high-fashion,
almost jewelry boutique when you're here.
Even the little cups that they
have are branded The Peninsula.
That's amazing. Wow, is that good. What the heck!
So, those were all of the public spaces here
at The Peninsula, and it's time to give it
a final Ambiance score. What better place
to do that than here on the helipad again.
So, The Peninsula has a lot of places
like this that make your jaw just drop.
That Rolls Royce fleet, that Roman Bath
area they have - all truly beautiful.
On the flip side of things, the gym is
definitely far from the most aesthetic
or beautiful or updated that we've seen.
It's also not the best spa or the best
treatments that we've seen as well,
and they're not the most interesting.
Other than that, it was very hard to find
anything to be critical of in the Ambiance.
I love the old. I love the new.
They blended them beautifully
together. I gave the ambience an 8.5 out of 10.
There are 300 rooms here at The Peninsula,
and 52 of those are suites. We're going to
take a look at the base level room first,
and then I'm going to show you two of the really
high end suites here. This base level room goes
anywhere between $500 to $700 US dollars
per night at the time of filming this.
And the room card they give you has
the door gods on it that you saw at
the beginning of this video, which
are the Chinese gods that protect
the guests of this hotel. It's also
got that Peninsula green on there.
So, just continues the motif and theme
through the hotel. Let's look in the room.
All right so, unfortunately, the
first thing that hits you when you
walk in the room is not the beauty
of the room, it's the smell of mold.
They definitely are dealing with a mold/mildew issue
in The Peninsula. Now it's humid. It rains a lot in Hong Kong.
It's an old building.It can happen, but I know many of you watching may
have allergies to mold or mildew, and
that will make it for a really tough stay.
The bed is very large. We're gonna test
that in just a minute, and of course,
I'm gonna sleep in it tonight and
give it a score in the morning. But
my favorite thing about this room are
the little hidden quirks and features.
There are many little interesting things
in here that I have truly never seen. I
want to show you all of those, and then
we'll get to the shower and the bed test.
Number one, the valet box. So
you push this button, opens up,
you open this and there's a valet collection
box that goes right into the hallway here so
someone can come by without coming in your
room and deliver things or pick things up.
Very interesting feature, especially in a base
level room. Over here in the writing desk,
the first is this button right here opens
up a full mirror with lights on either side.
It's very dramatic, very slow.
Push it again, put it down.
And also over here, in this drawer is a nail
dryer. So this is a modern nail dryer. You take
it off, set it down, and you can dry your nails,
in case you gave yourself a manicure in the room.
Two more over here: the coffee machine
has a little digital display to tell you
more about the Nespresso, and down below,
there's a full fax machine in the room,
just in case you need to scan and send some
faxes while you're staying at The Peninsula.
No, that is not all. You push this
button here that says ‘press’,
and an even more dramatic and
slow charging area pops out.
Slightly less strange, but still interesting:
this area behind me looks like there may not
be anything there, but watch this – open here’s
the TV, down here your snacks and amenities and
glassware. This side is your bar. This already was
opened. So everything here is also quite hidden.
Down below in the mini bar area, while
we're here, there's really not much.
You've got Kettle honey dijon
chips, sea salt and vinegar chips,
and some Peninsula gummy bears. One of
the weakest mini bars I've seen when
you have opportunities in Hong Kong for
incredible mini bar items that I'm sure
a lot of vendors and suppliers in the area
would love to work with the Peninsula on.
You've had 97 years to do it, you can definitely
do better than Kettle chips. Down below it says
snacks. You open it up and it's only alcohol
in this drawer, which is for purchase.
In the mini bar itself,
very simple drinks: waters,
tonic water, Sprite, Coke, Red Bull. Nothing
too interesting or exciting in the mini bar.
Now into the bathroom, as I mentioned, there
are a couple quirky things in here as well,
which mainly revolve around these old
phones. So by the sink and by the toilet,
there are these metal phones
that you can call the front desk.
There's also the tissue holder, which is
worked into the marbling here. And then
you have two mirrors, one on each
side. It's just a kind of strange
room in general. Even stranger is
the shower. Let's give it a test.
The Shower Test is three criteria points, that
is the Size, the Ease of Use, and the Pressure.
Size wise, it is decent, although there's
not a lot of room to move around in here,
and the ease of use is okay, although I really had
to figure out how to use this. Let me show you.
So this turns the shower on, both
of these, but that turns on the hand
faucet. To actually turn on the shower,
you have to pull this out. And it's very
hard to pull this out.
This does nothing.
You have to actually pull it out of the
wall to be able to get the top shower to go.
And then still, this is dripping over here, so
not very easy to use at all. Now the pressure
is where this shower really fails the test. Never
have I stayed somewhere where the shower pressure
is so strong that I actually don't want to
get in the shower. And that's the case here.
It feels like a fire hose or like you
are being power washed every time you
get in. I feel exfoliated because of
how hard the pressure is in the shower.
It's gotten to the point now where
it's uncomfortable and I don't want
to actually use it. Let me show you what
I'm talking about with this as well.
It looks like you can change the shower head
pressure here, right? You can spin it and
that will change it? No, this doesn't change
at all. You cannot change the shower head.
It's locked in place, so you have to take
an extremely high pressure shower. So look
how high pressure this is. It's
literally pushing back my finger.
Wow, I've never seen a shower like that.
Also the plumbing is quite old,
so when you turn on the shower,
it gargles through the sink as well, which
just makes the entire thing, again, unpleasant.
So that is the base level room. But as I
mentioned, there are two other penthouse
suites here. Let's take a look at those, and then
combine all of them for that final Room score.
The first of the two top suites here at The
Peninsula that I want to show you is the
Marco Polo suite. So this goes for $20,000
US dollars per night as of this recording.
And personally, I'm not sure that
it's worth it. It's two bedrooms. Yes,
all of the materials are very high quality,
but there are even higher level suites here
at the hotel, like The Peninsula Suite that
we'll see next and $20,000 a night is a lot.
However, there are some incredible details, like
the amenities that you receive complimentary
when you stay here, include these boxes
with little soaps that you can take home.
So this is a really nice perk to the room,
but I don't know, you decide.
Is it worth $20,000 a night?
Let's take a look at the Peninsula suite.
Welcome to The Peninsula Suite here at ThePeninsula.
So for an additional
$10,000 a night, you get THIS.
This is the technical penthouse
of this hotel, and it is huge,
but there's only one bedroom. Similar
amenities to what we saw in the last suite.
A lot of the materials are similar,
but you can just tell everything is
very elevated. You are truly
above the city of Hong Kong,
with the best views in the best
room that you could possibly have.
And as a bonus, it's the only room I've been in so
far at The Peninsula that doesn't smell like water
damage or mold, so that is a big plus.
Back in the standard room now,
it's time to change and get ready for sleep.
So I'm about to sleep in this bed and wake up
and give it a final room score in the morning.
But before I do that, I want to call the front
desk and order room service breakfast for a set
time. A little later in the service review portion
of this, we're going to see if it showed up
on time and if the food was hot and fresh.
I always order the same thing.
Let's call the front desk.
Hi there. Could I order breakfast
for tomorrow morning, please?
Could I order a black coffee
and an eggs Benedict please?
And then could I do that for 7am?
You as well, bye bye.
Let's get some sleep.
Okay, so the bed is quite firm. The mattress
itself is more like a brick than a mattress,
but, I will say the duvet cover and the sheets
and the pillows especially are so soft.
Not the ideal balance here, and
definitely far from the best
bed that I've slept in. Let's get
dressed and give it a Room score.
So I want to start with the negatives. That bed
was very firm and was not the best night's sleep.
The shower test was definitely
not passed. The mini bar was
lacking creativity and innovation,
and of course, that mold smell.
But on the positive side, there was some
very interesting things in this room that
I have not seen before. I really loved those
little hidden secrets and discovering them
throughout my stay. It's also a well designed
room, and if you include The Peninsula suite
and the Marco Polo suite, they really
do have an incredible eye for design.
The views here are spectacular
when it's not raining like today,
and the welcome amenities are really
wonderful. In fact, there were a couple
different amenities throughout the stay
that they brought and gave to the room,
including a bottle of non alcoholic champagne, and
these grapes that look like something straight out
of Beauty and the Beast and have been tempting
me, literally since they put them in here.
With all of that in mind, I
gave the room a 7.5 out of 10.
Getting into the Dining here:
there are seven restaurants
at The Peninsula. There is also a
full bar and a cafe. So like always,
I'm going to try all of them and
then give it a final Dining Score.
Good morning from the Veranda. So
this is their all day breakfast,
lunch, and dinner buffet option here, and the
buffet is looking really incredible. So it's
maybe not as large as others that we've
seen, like at the Four Seasons in Seoul,
but it does have a very high quality, very
well presented array of items to choose from.
So the displays here in the buffet are
really beautiful. I love how they put the
spices out here. So this is their Indian
section, and I'll say there's a couple of
dishes that maybe aren't as appetizing as the
others, but some of them that are amazing.
Overall, a very strong start to the
dining segment here at The Peninsula.
Now we are here in Spring Moon, which is
a one Michelin star Cantonese restaurant
at The Peninsula. They are famous for
two things. Number one is the XO sauce,
which they bottled and introduced to all of China.
So if you're familiar with that, we're
gonna try it right here. And number two,
is their handmade custard
mooncakes, which are so popular,
they've actually begun packaging
them and selling them as well.
So they have a tea sommelier heating up
little tea cups to then be presented as
a flavor enhancer for the dish
that we're about to be served.
If you've seen the channel, you know I am
a big fan of tea. I think this is one of
the most beautiful presentations that
you could have for a tea experience.
So before the multi-course
lunch that they have here,
they bring out a cold brew tea.
So it looks like champagne,
but it's actually a tea. So there's now been two
different types of tea that have been placed.
I want to really quickly talk about the glassware.
The incredible attention to detail that they have
here, and these are created by The Peninsula,
so you can't really get these anywhere.
Oh, wow. One thing with jasmine, it can
very easily become astringent. It just
means that you're over-steeping the
tea leaves, whether it's cold or hot.
And this is a very, very smooth jasmine tea. So
I've been very impressed with the tea selection.
This is a mango pudding. It's not the
most aesthetic, but let's hope the
flavor comes through here on it.
Okay, one thing about Hong Kong,
if you haven't been, it is on an island. So it's
a very modern city, but it's a very tropical,
very vibrant natural environment as
well, where they have tropical fruit.
So this is their very famous
fried rice with XO sauce.
It has a very delicate depth of flavor;
smokiness to it, the XO sauce, of course,
which, I have to be honest, I'm not sure if
I could identify that flavor specifically,
but you've seen a couple of Michelin
restaurants in hotels that I've put on
this channel in the past, and sometimes
you leave those still very much hungry.
That is not the case here at the Spring Moon.
So now we have a crispy chicken smoked with tea
leaf. This kind of reminds me of the peking duck
that we had in Seoul, just the skin specifically,
That really hit the spot. That's what I needed.
Very tender chicken. The tea leaves give it
a nice herbal, kind of herbaceous base to it.
Wow, another hit for Spring Moon.
So back in the lobby, this is where they
serve their legendary afternoon tea.
So they actually brought the afternoon
tea to Hong Kong for the very first time,
almost 100 years ago. It remains a
massive tradition here in the hotel,
and is very, very popular.
So I have to give it a try.
And I will say, at first glance, I'm a
little bit underwhelmed with the bread
that was used here and some of the other
things. But you never know until you try it.
So I'm gonna hold judgment
till we get through all of
these different trays here. Let's dive into this.
So you've got three different tiers here.
You've got your top tier, which is desserts,
your middle tier, which is your finger
foods, and then you have the scones.
The most iconic, the most
famous, are these scones,
and they have been for 100 years. They truly
have not changed this recipe for 100 years.
Wow. So soft. Smells incredible.
I can already tell this is a big
difference from what we had at the Signiel
afternoon tea in Seoul, South Korea.
Wow. That is such an incredible flavor. It's
like a honey sweet bread. It's so dense,
it's not too dry, it's very fluffy.
That is is how you do a scone with
afternoon tea - and it makes sense why they
haven't changed the recipe in almost 100 years.
We have salmon on what looks like a hamburger bun
with a lettuce leaf and a little bit of radish
on top. Again, I just think that there's
really an opportunity here for refinement,
elevation and visual improvement,
but that is a very nice flavor.
So so fresh, really tasty.
Last, but not least, here we have our cup of
strawberries that have this glitter - like
edible glitter - that they put on top of it.
Look: you can't go wrong with strawberries
and cream, one of the best
flavors I think on this planet.
My overall thoughts on the tea set is that it is
traditional, and they've stuck to the traditional
way of doing an afternoon tea. So maybe some
room and some opportunity for improvement.
Now the last lunch location here is Imasa,
which is a Japanese light bites
restaurant. They have sushi and sashimi.
They brought out the appetizer dish, which
is on this beautiful tray. So it's tomato,
it's white shrimp, tofu, and abalone.
That is really special. You can tell
when you have really great sashimi.
It's not overpowering. Doesn't taste
like the ocean. That's what you've
got here. Really light and lovely.
I would have this breakfast, lunch and dinner.
So being from California, I did order the
California roll to see. There's some very
nice roe on the outside. Look how beautiful
that is. A nice little edible flower.
There's a lot of roe on that. The thing
with roe is, I love it on top of sushi rolls.
It can be a little bit fishy if you have a lot.
So it is literally coating the
outside of the sushi roll for
that one. It's a little bit
overpowering on that flavor.
The highlight, funnily enough, of
this display here, is the wasabi.
Don't know what to tell you, they
just really got that right.
So it's now time for a quick coffee break
here in The Peninsula Cafe and Boutique.
So this is an adorable, little
cafe that they have here,
that has an aquamarin/ teal color about
it. It has a beautiful design, again,
very distinct from the rest of the hotel, and
also quite far from everything else in the hotel.
So this is located in The Peninsula
Arcade, which you saw earlier in
this review. And it's a full coffee shop
here that's very quiet and very peaceful.
There's a separate menu here
at the Peninsula Boutique,
and most of it revolves around
sourdough bread or mango.
It depends on the season, that does
change. I ordered the most popular drink,
which is their mango fizzy drink. And you can
see here the presentation is really beautiful.
There's a little bear that's made out
of porcelain with the Peninsula on top.
Looks like some mango ice cream and some mint.
Here we go, let’s see if it tastes as
good as it looks. Whoa. So so interesting.
There's really thick pieces of mango in there,
and it's sparkling, so it actually is
fizzy – not my favorite drink. I think
just because of the chunks in there kind of
give it a weird texture, but a great flavor.
The ice cream is actually more of a custard.
Now it's time for the main event, the dinners.
We're here in Gaddi’s, which is a 71 year
old Michelin starred French restaurant.
I'm going to try one of the most popular
things on the menu, their wagyu steak.
Wow, beautiful presentation.
So this is the wagyu steak. It's one of
the most popular things on the menu here
at Gaddi’s. Everything is beautifully plated.
Honestly, you don't even need the béarnaise,
or really, any of the garnish on
here. This is such an incredible cut.
Wow. So that is A5 wagyu. It's medium rare.
There's a couple of little side dishes here.
So they have some little mini mushrooms, almost a
little cannoli, but it's actually a crispy potato
with some edible flowers on the top.
Very crunchy, soft, flavorful inside.
If I lived in Hong Kong and I could,
I would come here all the time just for
this dish. This is truly excellent.
Yet another hit for the Peninsula
in the dining segment here.
So the word Chesa actually means “Inn”
and it definitely feels like a cozy,
traditional Swiss chalet in here.
One thing that's interesting is that
it looks like there are windows
but they actually aren't real,
so it gives you that kind of quiet and dark,
intimate feeling when you're dining here.
So as they're coming around pouring water,
I noticed that the glassware that
they use are different Swiss Alps.
So these are actually mountains from Switzerland
in the glass itself, which is such a cool
and unique detail here in the restaurant,
there's a lot of that throughout this room.
So this is one of their two most famous
dishes here: this is the raclette,
which is a type of cheese that has potato on top.
You're supposed to smash the potato into the
cheese, wrap it in and then give it a try. So
here we go.
Mm, oh,
wow is that good. Really great
cheese for that potato, though.
So here we have it, the star of the show. This
is the cheese fondue, the main course here,
and they come out with a couple of interesting
sides, which I'm a little shocked about.
So this is just cooked macaroni. Looks like maybe
boiled potatoes on the side here, just very plain,
which is interesting. I'm assuming the
cheese has a really strong flavor, so maybe
the potatoes and macaroni are meant to just kind
of complement that with something to dip it in.
Then, of course, you have the traditional bread.
Significantly different flavor than I expected.
You can taste a little bit of the bacon,
but there's a lot of undertones
to the flavor of the fondue.
The cheese almost tastes like it was cooked with
wine. It has an almost alcoholic taste to
it, definitely different than I expected.
I think it's a more traditional
fondue than any that I've ever had,
and I definitely like it. It's also
very heavy. So just keep that in mind.
You have a whole pot of this, and
you're gonna be wheeled outta here.
What a distinct and different restaurant to
offer here. I mean, truly, for breakfast,
you could have Cantonese food at
the buffet over at The Veranda,
and then for dinner, come over here and
have Swiss as if you're in the Alps.
It's really impressive. I haven't
seen many hotels like that.
So if that very Swiss dinner wasn't enough,
they just brought out their
signature dessert here. Look at this.
It's a little house made out of
chocolate with a pistachio base
around it to look like grass. And then
they give you chocolate sauce that you
drizzle on top of the house.
I have to see what's inside.
So, wow. So the surprise inside is vanilla
ice cream. That is a cool dessert.
So before we sit down for dinner at Felix here,
I want to get a cocktail at the molecular bar.
So they use this chemistry equipment
behind me to make some of their drinks,
and I ordered a pretty interesting
one. What they say is the most popular.
We are still in the Peninsula Hotel,
mind you, and this restaurant feels
like I have completely been transported to
a futuristic, modern restaurant and bar.
I heard the menu is also very different as well.
One thing that's cool about the restaurant
here is that all of the chairs have the
faces of the staff of the Peninsula that
have been here for more than 20 years.
So once you've been at the Peninsula
for more than 20 years, they put your
picture on one of the chairs in Felix, and
there are a lot of chairs in this room.
So before we go to the bar and
give it that final dining score,
I want to add two little bonuses for you.
So this is inside a Michelin starred kitchen.
Now we've looked inside Michelin kitchens before,
but remember, every chef does
it a little bit differently.
I also want to show you something
they call the Chocolate Room.
So in this room, they create custom by
hand chocolate creations for guests,
for various celebrations like New
Year's or birthdays or weddings.
And everything here is made by hand using
these two chocolate mixers right in front
of you. Really an amazing room that
you don't see very often at a hotel.
Let's go to the bar.
Now, the primary bar here at the
Peninsula is called The Bar. They
have live music every single night,
including a pianist and sometimes jazz.
It's a very comfortable, cozy, dark wood, dark
leather kind of lounge feel. It actually feels
completely separate from the hotel, totally
different than the rest of the interior.
They have some very unique cocktails on
the menu, like the Long Life Elixir here,
which I absolutely have to try.
Whew,
that was a lot of dining here at the
Peninsula, an incredibly impressive,
diverse display of culinary art in
all of the different restaurants here.
My only critique is that not every dish was
extraordinary. There were a couple that maybe
could have been taken a look at in the buffet or
in some of the dishes at the Felix, for example,
but really it is hard to critique when that's
only about 5% of all of the meals that I had.
You saw the plating, the
presentation, the serving,
everything was top notch. I gave the dining
here at the Peninsula a 9 out of 10.
Now let's talk about the Service, which is
a very important part of any luxury stay.
All right, it is 6:54, so they arrived six
minutes early with the breakfast Service
Test here. This is the Eggs Benedict and
the hot coffee that I ordered last night.
It is looking very appetizing, minimalistic. It
has a zucchini and an another kind of squash here.
The coffee has this perfectly clean silver polish
to it. So a fun fact about the silver here,
they use over 20,000 pieces of silverware
every single day here at The Peninsula,
and someone polishes them by hand to be used.
They have over 40,000 in their collection.
They have a little marker here that
says coffee. This one says cream.
Let's test how fresh it is.
Whew, very hot, very good.
They definitely passed the breakfast Service
Test. In fact, this is the first hotel on the
channel where the breakfast has arrived
before the time that it was expected.
We won't know the official service score,
however, until we do that Service Test.
Now, the Service Test is the part of the
review where I call the front desk and
ask for something a little bit strange
that they're not used to accommodating.
I've asked for a lot of strange things on
the channel in the past, and it's more about
if they're able or willing to accommodate
it, rather than actually accomplishing it.
Here at the peninsula, you
saw that Chocolate Room,
which really got me thinking. Who you
didn't meet is the head chocolatier,
who is really the Willy Wonka of the Peninsula,
and claims he can make anything out of chocolate.
So I put this survey out to all
of you to see what you think we
should have him make, and this was the winner.
Let's give him a call.
So I was actually wondering if you
could make a camera out of chocolate?
Is it possible to have that
set up in the room as well?
Okay, great.
So he is able to make a camera
and bring it up to the room.
Okay, amazing. I'm looking forward to seeing it.
Pretty cool. Let's go talk about the service at
the hotel in general, and then come back and see
what a camera made out of chocolate looks like.
Couple things that happened in the hotel: I needed
a scissors to cut something, and they delivered it
on a silver tray with a nice fabric underneath it.
Another time, something happened
with my camera during filming,
and the microphone stopped working.
One of the staff offered to go all the way to
the store and pick up the thing that I needed
and just bill it to the room at the exact
price with no surcharge or anything extra.
Every staff that I've interacted with or come
into contact with has been so kind and so nice.
They greet you by your last name, escort
you everywhere you need to go, for example,
even in the bathroom, which, of course, I didn't
film, there's a staff in every single men's room
throughout the hotel, making sure you have
a hand towel and everything that you need.
Sometimes the hotel was truly empty, and they
would still have areas like that staffed.
Anywhere that you go in the hotel, anywhere in
the restaurant, they're always accommodating,
always thinking of ways to go
out of their way to support you.
All right, so back in the room to see
if they set up our chocolate camera…
What is this here? So they set out a record
from the Gaddi’s restaurant. That's amazing.
All right, let's see if we have our camera.
Wow, look at this. Oh, this is beautiful.
You've got to be kidding me about that.
Wow. Very impressive pass for the service
test here. Not only did they make a camera,
as requested by all of you, they
also put Ryan's Travel Journal,
and I'm at a loss for words. Look at that. Wow.
It even says The Peninsula on the front of it.
He really is the Willy Wonka of the Peninsula.
But I think we do have to give it a try,
because that's what it was made for, right?
I feel like to be respectful,
I have to eat the whole thing.
What an incredible life experience
that was. I'm blown away. Did not
think they'd be able to do that here
at the Peninsula, but they really did.
That was one of the best service test
results I've ever seen. And truly,
I wish I could have taken it home,
but that's the second best option.
One thing that I didn't mention earlier
is when I went downstairs to walk around
a little bit and to talk about the service
at the hotel while this was getting made,
they did tell me that this would be
$300 US dollars for this display.
Now the display was already set up at that point.
It was already far past the point where I could
have said no, and I'm not complaining at all. I
am totally happy to pay that, but they definitely
should have checked beforehand on the phone to
make sure that the price made sense for the piece.
Definitely not that big of a deal.
Let's give it an official service score.
So as you saw already, they absolutely
knocked the service test completely out
of the park. They were also early
with the breakfast service test,
which has never been done before
in any of these hotel reviews.
Generally around the hotel, they were
always extraordinarily attentive,
supportive, helpful, and they were overstaffed
everywhere, which was a really nice touch.
There were only a few minor things that I
would adjust. Compared to other luxury hotels,
it did feel like there was an air
of stress amongst the staff. I've
been places where the staff feel
joyous and happy to be there,
and that wasn't as much the case here at the
Peninsula, but it was a minor, minor difference.
Additionally, there wasn't enough
waters in the room. It felt like
I was always asking for more water or
trying to find waters around the hotel,
and there was no welcome drink when you first
check in, which is just a small detail, but it
can make a big difference when you're dehydrated
from a long flight from Los Angeles, for example.
With all of this in mind, but all of the
really exceptional things standing out,
I gave the service a 9 out of 10.
Now for the It-Factor. The It-Factor
is that special thing about a hotel that you
can't really put your finger on. It's the
indescribables, the thing that you want
to tell your friends and family about,
or the reason why you keep coming back.
Part of the It-Factor of the hotel is also
the Value, and the price point per night is
quite high for the city of Hong Kong,
but it's not the highest in the city.
You also have access to some of their
facilities, like the pool here that you
saw earlier, the Rolls Royce fleet, but many
of those things are actually for purchase.
Now, the things that are included here in the
hotel include yoga and some fitness activities,
but they are pretty sparse in the calendar,
and we've seen much better activities at
other hotels that are complimentary,
like in Costa Rica, for example.
So you saw the Rolls Royce fleet earlier
in this review, and now we are inside of
one. These Rolls Royces can be booked for
anywhere between 2,500 to 4,800 Hong Kong
dollars per hour, and they'll take you
anywhere you want to go in Hong Kong.
One other fun thing about this Rolls Royce is
the seats back here are not only incredibly
comfortable, I mean, there's a very plush carpet
underneath my shoes, they also have a massage
function that you can literally turn on and get
a massage while you're driving through Hong Kong.
I've never seen something like
this at a luxury hotel before,
where the house car is this caliber
and they have this many of them.
Now, before I give The Peninsula an official
It-Factor score, I want to say a special thank
you to The Peninsula team, who went way out
of their way to make sure I could film the
most comprehensive review possible. They opened
every single door, and I am incredibly grateful.
Now for the It-Factor. Some of the
things that you didn't see at this
hotel include the facade of the building
actually changing throughout the year.
So during the holidays, they wrap the front
in this blue ribbon that you see here,
and during Chinese New Year, it's red lanterns.
Generally speaking, you really do have a sense
of place when you're staying here. It has a lot
of gravitas and power here in the city of Hong
Kong, I gave the It-Factor a 7.5 out of 10.
So there you have it. That was The Peninsula
Hotel. I was very impressed with this stay;
they have definitely refined this hotel
over the course of 100 years of history.
I recommend it next time you're in the city.
Unfortunately, it is time to check out
now and give it that final score out of
50. So if you total together all of
the numbers throughout this review…
I gave the Peninsula Hotel here
in Hong Kong a 41 out of 50.
Thanks so much for watching. I'm Ryan
Walker, and we'll see you on the next one!